Hey, what's going on man? Man, how you doing? Good. How you doing?
How's your week been? Not too bad. Not too bad. How about you? Good, good,
good. Saturday's Friday, though. Ready for lunch? Yes. Oh, man, I,
I'm just dragging usually by the, by Friday afternoon, so, yeah. I also, man,
I hurt my back. I was working out earlier this week, and it's not,
I've been like, completely debilitated. It's crazy. Like I can barely stand up.
I just, and it, it ironically sitting down hurts it even more.
I just dying to like, lay on my couch for a little bit. Um, anyways,
what were you doing? How did you, what'd you strength? Strength? I was, yeah,
I go to the gym. I, uh, I, I lift, I, I played football in college, so it's,
it kind of been in me forever. And I still brutally competitive,
so I like to work out and go to the gym and lift,
and sometimes I lift stuff that's way heavier than I need to be lifting at my
age. I have that same problem too. So I'm, I'm,
I'm learning my lesson as I get older that my body is not 21 years old anymore,
you know? Exactly. Um, okay, cool.
So appreciate you jumping on.
I'm gonna share my screen just so we can get through this presentation. Um,
so essentially what I'm gonna try and get through here,
we got a lot of stuff to look at. Um,
we're just go through what I found and then just run you through what I think
would be the best way for us to engage together and everything that would be
included in that. So if not, you can still walk away with, I think, um, some,
some pretty good learnings here,
and at least some strategies that you'd be able to apply on your own. So,
first page here, I'll send this deck to you afterwards too,
so you can read all the information in here.
Essentially what this just says is that, uh, you know,
I took a good look at basically trying to determine what I think is gonna be the
best way for you to generate leads.
And basically it's the same as we talked about before, before local search,
right? Getting ranked in the local maps pack,
and then also some stuff with LSAs, which is,
I look at as kind of like a small extension of, of, of the maps pack.
It's really run by the same profile, which is your Google business profile.
So getting 'em to rank organically,
but then also small paid spend to pick up leads in the meantime, right? And,
um, get the ball rolling.
So the screenshot over here is a piece of software that we use to track maps
pack ranking, right? So this is, uh, it's cut off a little bit,
but it's the te uh, the Tempe area. Um,
and basically this is, uh, looking at the keyword,
D u i attorney Tempe, right? So you can see,
I'm sure your office is literally probably like right under this.
I'm not sure if you can see the map underneath this, uh,
underneath this basically, yeah. Can see the area. Yeah. Yeah.
Basically outside of, you know, a very, very,
very small like 0.1 mile radius around your office,
your profile's basically not found. Um, and when I google that too, uh,
over here, you know, um, this is d u i attorney, uh, Tempe,
uh, these are the LSAs up here, by the way, the sponsored ones, you're in here,
but you're down there, you are, you're,
you're in like position nine or 10 for the overall greater search, right? Um,
so this is really what we want to focus on is punching up
where we at, punching these rankings up as far of a radius as we can go. Um,
because the further the radius, I mean, obviously the more traffic,
the more calls that we're gonna get. Um, and it's,
it's a bit of a process because Google ranks,
there's a, a, a ton of ranking factors that go into this.
Local maps pack reviews is a big one. Um,
but also proximity of searching, right?
So if somebody's in Miami searching for Tempe,
which they probably wouldn't be anyways, right? But it's,
it's much more difficult to rank because of the proximity.
So a lot of the times people are searching within this radius, right?
But the goal is to punch up and give your profile as much authority as possible,
because what's gonna happen is you're just basically gonna see a ripple effect
across, across your region, right? And then we get a statistic up there.
So this screenshot here is from a tool called arus,
which you'll be seeing a lot of, essentially. It's difficult to see, I know,
but it's basically just showing you that you don't really have that much organic
traffic coming in right now, which I think you're aware of, right? Um,
but we'll be reviewing this software as we go through and look at some
competitors to give you some context, right?
Because some of your competitors are actually doing pretty well. Um,
and we'll take a look at them. So this year, again,
I know this is difficult to see, uh, lemme just like punch up the,
so I'll just go through these one by one with you here. Um,
this is a little bit more of kind of like a,
looking at the specifics of your website and trying to figure out why and what
we can do to improve it as a course of actions to get you to rank. So,
first one here, uh, website architecture navigation need to be reorganized.
I'll just pop over to your website here. So the top level nav up here, did you,
I know you had somebody build this.
Did they set this up for you or did you Yeah, they did. They set it all up,
yeah. Okay. The only thing I do is I go in and I add blogs. I mean,
that's really the only thing I do with it. So, yeah,
I watched a bunch of videos. I love that you make video, by the way. Um, it's,
I know it's a pain in the ass. Um, it's, um,
but that could be something too that we could chat about. You know,
it's just some free consulting to, I,
I don't know if you've seen my YouTube channel,
but I do a lot of stuff on YouTube, um, and, uh,
got a pretty good feel for what the YouTube algorithm is looking at,
so we could chat about that as well. Mm-hmm. Um,
but essentially just structuring this in a way,
this top level navigation up here from a search engine point of view,
this is what Google looks at as like your main filing cabinet, right?
So in terms of organizing it, and then also the pages that are on it,
the order of them, the targeting of them. Um,
when we boil this down to what's in here, it really comes down to two things.
It's really content and links, right?
So I put that as kind of like a grouping under content,
a little bit of technical work. Um, the good thing is,
and when we start talking about the scope tool,
you'll see that you don't need a lot of technical work, right?
Which is for a website of your size, if somebody's telling you otherwise,
they're just trying to take money outta your pocket. Um,
so also small things too, like call to actions, I wanna show you.
So you have like a contact us up here. It's pretty standard, I get it, right?
But small things like this,
especially when we're talking about punching up traffic a little bit,
this is actually one of our clients. Um, he's a tax attorney in, uh, San Diego.
And just small little things like this in terms of making the call to action a
little bit more appeasing again,
if we can just convert one or two more people per month, um, yeah,
small things make a big difference in the long run, you know what I mean? Um,
so just kind of like an overall website audit for overall copy structure
conversion. Just make sure it's set up properly.
We're not talking about like a redesign or anything here.
We're just talking about more of the, the experience of the website.
So this is probably the biggest, the biggest opportunity here too,
in terms of the website, outside of the actual local maps pack. Um,
and I'll show you why,
but you're missing some key content to fulfill what we call like the full
customer journey. So I'm gonna jump down here to the slide down here. This is,
um, a marketing funnel, right? Top, middle, bottom, right?
So we take this and we map this to what we call search intent.
So when somebody's looking for, you know,
d u i attorney and all the things that are associated with it,
we want to try and build content to satisfy those searches.
So that's really where blog content comes in.
For more of this like top funnel stuff, the bottom funnel stuff,
which is where a large majority of your phone calls are gonna come from,
are like the action-based keywords. So I'm ready to hire an attorney now,
d u i attorney, and I'm just gonna pick from a list call and see who I like,
right?
So this is gonna be like coming from LSAs and also your Google business profile,
because this search is going to trigger this very
like, action based results.
It's basically all ads and then actual business websites, right? Um,
but that is only people are in your local area only gonna be searching for that
so much, right? We can't increase the amount that people are searching for. Um,
but what we can do is we can try and find keywords that maybe aren't directly
looking to hire right now, but maybe a step before hiring you right now. Um,
and that's really where content is very, is very, very useful and very lethal.
And I'll show you on some of our other law firm websites,
how we've used that to just explode their traffic. Mm-hmm. Um,
so one of the things that we'd like to do too though, is again, keeping in mind,
this is the goal down here, action-based keywords.
And sometimes we have to do a little digging to find new ones and then then
create content around it.
So one of the ones that I found on your website is this underage or baby d u i,
right? Love the video content is solid. There's no major issue with it.
It's just the targeting of it, right?
Understanding how people are searching for this, because essentially, again,
I'm not a, a legal expert, but underage, D u i, right?
For somebody who's under the age.
So I would imagine that a parent might be searching for that.
Something along those lines.
So when we take that and we search for that underage d u i,
the page that you have here isn't ranking right anywhere. It's not to be found,
but you can see down here that this is actually a really good result because a
bunch of your competitors are, this guy here, Tobin Law,
I'll show you some of this traffic.
He's doing a really good job of picking up a bunch of searches like this too,
right?
So this here is a conversion-based keyword that you just don't have the right
content on your website for. It's just not formatted properly. So again,
these are like small,
small execution things that it takes a very skilled eye to pick up and see.
'cause most people might see us and be like, yeah, you have the page,
but it's not formatted for the intent properly, right? I mean,
that's a large part of what we'll be doing is improving content. Um, so,
um, and then also just key website landing pages in terms of your bottom funnel
pages. We just go through and, um, basically optimize these on hand for you.
We'll add more depth, um, the writing as aside,
but you can just see this is very thin in terms of overall volume, right? So,
you know, the first company that I,
that I worked with about a year ago told me to keep all of my blogs at about 300
words. That's why a lot of those are so short. Yeah.
Recently I've been trying to add go 1200 to 1500. I mean, is that,
do you think that's appropriate length? It depends on the query, right?
And that's, and that's really where we come in handy, right?
Because what we do is we build you a, a whole content map where if you're like,
I have some time, Ryan, I, I wanna create some content videos,
and like you have a map in front of you that will tell you this is what the
topic should be, this is how long it should be.
These are like the supporting kind of keywords that should be included,
and we'll also help you optimize it, right?
But this is one of your competitors here who's ranking for a bunch of really
good keywords, and you can just kind of see how long, um, you know,
even underneath the form this,
I know an s e o did this because you put it underneath the form to try and hide
it, but like, it's just a very, very much longer form page,
and it's super basic, right? I hate that Google does this, but like, it's just,
it's just what it is. Longer pages ranked better, you know, um,
especially around really competitive, uh, really competitive searches.
That makes sense.
So we'd want to go through and reoptimize all of your bottom funnel pages,
and we have writers, so we just go in and do the writing for you.
You approve it, obviously, but, uh, you know, we can take that off your plate.
That's all included in our, our quote. Also,
just some small layout improvements too, um,
in terms of the structure and layout of these pages a little bit,
just to make them get indexed a little bit better. Very,
very small stuff that we do with our developer just to clean up the performance
of the pages. Okay? Um, and then the big thing here too,
the other big one is just link building.
Are you familiar with link building at all?
I just a little bit very basic knowledge. Okay.
I'm aware of it though. Okay. Let me,
let me break it down for you and put it into context of,
of why it's so important. So, um, a link is like, let's say, I don't know,
let's say Huffington Post writes an article about the best D u I attorneys in
Tempe, hypothetically not saying that they would, right?
And they listed out 10 of you, and then within it,
it includes a link back to your website so people can go and discover and read
more. That actual link is incredibly important to s e o.
The reason is because the way that Google sees it is that Google actually will
crawl from page to page through links. So like,
when two websites are linked together,
that's how Google will discover another page. What it also does,
it also associates it with that website, right? So for example,
if the Huffington Post, which is a big popular website,
is talking about your website, Google's like, oh, okay,
like he's sitting at the cool kid table, so therefore he must be cool, right?
So the more of those links that we pick up,
the more authoritative your website becomes.
So it's basically like you're getting mentioned, it's almost like PR,
if you will, right? Like you get a a, a news article, right?
That talks about it just associates your website positively and ranks you up.
Now the key to link building is making sure that we're getting on relevant
websites, right? Like getting mentioned on, I don't know,
website about space or NASA doesn't really help you out,
but if we can get you on relevant legal websites, it's really impactful. Now,
the way that, that, uh, materializes,
so let me zoom in here so you can see this.
So this is your website in a tool called arus. Um,
so what you're looking at here is kind of like a very rudimentary performance
dashboard. So you can see that back links right here. It says 256,
but it's really 25.
So basically 25 other websites have talked about you and linked back to you,
right? And it's probably stuff like, I dunno, like fine law,
whatever that is stuff right now, if we look at your competitor here, Tobin Law,
you can see he's got 352 domains. So that's a a, a pretty big discrepancy there,
right? And then if we go here too, you can also see your,
I like to look at the traffic value because what this tells us is if you were to
pay for these keywords for paid search,
this is how much it would cost per month, right?
So you can see your website's not really ranking for anything of major value,
but then when we pop over to his website, uh,
he's got about $62,000 in paid traffic coming in. So really, really,
really good keywords that he's ranked for. He doesn't have a ton of traffic,
but that's key here, right? Is he's got really,
really good high quality keywords that if you like, if you're,
if you're ranking for any d u I term, really we're talking about 200, 300,
$400 per click. Um, so that's how this number is calculated.
So you can just see basically the traffic value and the business value that he's
getting from basically just ranking for these keywords that you could be ranking
for. Does that make sense? Yeah, absolutely. So, um,
let me pop back over here. Okay. So do you have any questions on,
on these kind of like, strategies? No, no, no.
I appreciate you going through those. No. Okay, perfect. So,
very straightforward here. We're a very results driven agency.
We like to clearly document what our goals are before getting into engagement.
So number one is just correct the performance of the website in terms of the
structure, the content. Uh,
number two is gonna be to improve your queued rankings,
specifically in the local maps pack for anything around D U I. Um,
and then final and foremost,
and most important is driving phone calls and leads, right?
So we're gonna be measuring against all these things.
We put together a dashboard that all of our clients have access to where you can
clearly see, um, the performance of the campaign, right? Okay. As far as, um,
is, is it, is it just d u i or would you guys focus on that?
That would be the primary focus from the local point of view.
Because the challenge is, so, like the short answer is no, right?
The whole website we'd be optimizing, but like the local profile itself,
unless we could get you other locations, right?
So this is something that we're starting to do a little bit more with some of
our larger law firm clients that we get to rank in their market
completely. And then it's kinda like, okay, well what else can we do?
'cause we're, these phone calls are very valuable to us. Well,
it's like what we can do is we can help you find an office location,
not a Regis 'cause they get declined, but like actual commercial space, 500,
a thousand bucks a month, whatever it is in adjourning city or market.
So we're basically helping people go on a new market. So, and if we do that,
or if you get another office,
we could try getting the same office verified under another Google business
profile. But basically you can open that up under,
and we can list it d u i and some other things that you do,
but for the most part, it's gonna pick up relevancy for one. Got it.
So unless you have a separate Google business profile, so, and keep in mind,
right, this is just, sorry, hold on one second. My dog's about to go nuts.
So, um, you know, this is built for D U I,
but if there was another that was just based on our previous conversation,
if there was another one that you wanted to focus on, then, you know,
we just kind of swap out that, that focus No DUI is actually Yeah, that,
that would be the,
that would be the bread and butter right there if we could get those. Yeah.
And I, the thing is, when, when it comes to internet leads too, you know,
I was actually just talking to a law firm before this too, about how their,
you know, they're their PI firm and d u i is their best internet focus because
of the intent. Like for example, if I'm looking for a law firm for business,
I would like post on my Instagram story or ask for a referral maybe, et cetera.
But for D U I, I'm probably not gonna post that. I'm probably gonna,
I want go through a little bit more of private process, right?
Searching on my own, you know, calling in the privacy, whatever.
So it actually lends very well to, um,
good volume and also good quality of the, of the calls as well. Um,
so getting in that to now about how we would attack this.
So we operate on what are called sprints. Um,
essentially it's just a way of saying that we batch our work into shorter
cycles, right? So where some firms will be like, oh yeah,
we're gonna do keyword research every month. We don't. We do it at once.
It's just faster, it's more effective. We like to get the,
the bulk of the work done up front, um, and just move quicker.
So the first sprint that we do is what we call our foundational sprint.
So this is essentially like the architecture. This is looking at keywords,
this is looking at, um, anything technical on the website.
We'll also do like an audit, audit,
make sure that nothing is holding you back technically. Website speed,
stuff like that. Um, that's sprint number one. Then we get into local stuff,
and this is something that we do on a monthly basis in terms of like citation
building. We'll also do, uh,
we'll help you to automate your review process in terms of reaching out to
people via email. Um, getting reviews is, is a humongous part about this.
I know we'd spoken about that before. Um, we'll also do, uh,
essentially local link building on like localized websites.
So what we just talked about. But instead of like huffing and post,
think anything local in your area that really helps drive home good amount of
relevancy. Uh, the next print is content. So like I said, we have writers,
we handle everything unless you wanted to do the writing, but for the most part,
we'd prefer to do it to just sprint it out and get it done with. Um,
so basically we would be,
in terms of the scope of the amount of content over the period, it's uh,
I think it was between 12 and 20 pieces of content between the current
landing pages that you have.
That would probably be like in the first two or three months. Um,
and then after we get through that,
then we'd be focusing a lot more on like blog content,
more of the top funnel stuff, improving the assets that you have. Um,
'cause that's the thing is you've got a lot of it done right,
and we can just kind of repurpose that, build it longer, you know, retarget it,
refocus it, um, and hopefully get it to rank pretty quickly. Okay.
And then, uh, the final one is a link sprint. So this is we hand,
so essentially since we work with so many law firms,
we've got a really good database of contacts of legal websites that we can reach
out to. Um, so we handle all like the research, the prospecting.
Sometimes we have to do a little content writing to get like featured in an
article. Um, we handle all that. And then the final piece is, like I said,
it's just a tracking. So you get a dashboard call it tracks, calls,
traffic rankings, um, all the main KPIs. Do you have any questions on that? No.
No. Okay, great. So I do wanna share two quick case studies with you.
And I actually wanna pop over and show you this in,
in real time because I realized that this screenshot is a couple months old.
So this is one, uh, this is actually a local firm here in Miami, qto Law Group.
Um, and remember I showed you these,
I'm gonna show you, there's an hre too. So you can see, um,
$56,000 a month of traffic. And this is also the traffic growth.
You can just see the amount of organic traffic they've gotten, basically. Yeah,
it's nuts. Um, our, our s e o team is, is really, really amazing.
You can also see like the number of links,
the number of keywords that they're ranking for. Um, they do very, very well.
Another big one is braman. Um, so this is the website that I already showed you.
Uh, I can just pop this over here and show you 319,000 in traffic. Yeah,
I mean they're, um, he's currently in the process of,
I think he's hiring like five more attorneys. He hired, like,
he's building a full sales team now. It's like nuts. I mean, the guy's a,
a monster right on his own. Um, but we really came in and poured gasoline,
uh, on his, it's his business has just been, it's been crushing it. Um,
so yeah,
just a couple of relevant case studies that I wanna share with you as well. Um,
so let's talk about the scope and the pricing.
So let me zoom in on this so you can see it. So,
um, for everything I was, we come in right at $4,000 per month.
Um, we have no long-term agreements. If at any point you're not happy, you know,
you can walk. Um, think we talked about that. This is just a breakdown too.
So you can see kind of like the focus of the first month. Like I said,
we sprint out all like the technical stuff, the keywords in the first month,
get that done. Um, local ss e o is ongoing,
the reporting and analytics is ongoing.
Then the content and links are down here. So a little bit about how that works.
So essentially this content investment will get you four pieces of content
per month, right? So that's landing pages, that's, um, any,
any scope of content in terms of written content. And then the links down here.
We actually don't really make much money on these links because a lot of it just
goes out to like pay for content. So this,
you get anywhere from seven to 10 links per month on a regular basis, um,
once we get everything up and running.
So we're literally just taking that outta that budget from there.
So the good thing about the way that we operate too is that I like to tell
people that you're also getting, you know,
we're tracking the things that matter, right? Phone calls, leads, et cetera.
But you're also getting tangible assets, right? In terms of content assets,
in terms of link assets that you can see every month, which clients love,
because a lot of agencies don't report on this stuff because they just do a
s****y job, frankly, of, of content writing and link building. Um, we don't,
we're very, very good at it. So you get a report that show you, again,
the content, um, the links every single month as well.
So you have those tangible assets too that help to justify some of our costs as
well. So do you have any questions on this? No, no, I don't. Okay, great.
So you can kind of breeze through the rest of these two. This is myself,
my partner, uh, some of the people on the team that you'd be working with, um,
real quick too, because you did find us through an ad.
So you probably don't know that much about us. Um,
something I, yeah, I've, I've, I've, okay, perfect. Yeah, I mean, go ahead,
bill. Yeah, I, I, I mean, something that I'm, I'm really, really proud of is,
is our reputation and our commitment to our craft and our work.
And I think if you look us up, you ask around about us,
I don't even think a competitor would have a bad thing to say about us, um,
because of how much we do in the marketing community in terms of, uh, you know,
contributing at conferences.
I'm actually going to Europe next month to speak at a,
a pretty large conference as a headliner, all about marketing at s e o. Um,
we've been featured pretty much everywhere. Again,
Google my name or the company's name and you'll see our reviews. You'll see, um,
the great things that people have to stay for us. Um, also, like I said, I mean,
I encourage you to check out my YouTube channel. Um,
this is something that I live and breathe at every single day. Um,
it's a business, but it's also fortunately aligns with what I enjoy doing,
which is growing businesses. Um, the other cool thing,
kind of the final note here is that we do have a sister company called the
Blueprint Training, where we actually have trained over 3000 agencies.
It's actually a bigger business than this agency business itself. Um,
so I kind of like jokingly like to say that there's a pretty good chance that we
actually trained your s e o agency or anyone that you've worked with in the
past. That's awesome. Um, yeah, a lot of it stems from this book that we wrote.
And this just, we have,
we're a very type a process focused agency where nothing falls through the
cracks. Um, you know, as a business owner myself,
I understand what matters and that's, um, you know,
the work in the queue research is cool, but like,
if it's not making people money, then um, it doesn't really matter. And it's,
it's really everything that flows through this business, right? Um, mm-hmm.
So that's whole presentation. Like I said,
I'll follow up with an email to you on this. Do you have any questions?
Anything? Yeah, with, um, you,
you had mentioned something about the pay-per-click,
also kind of just running a, a small spend campaign. Yeah. Um,
so as far as that would go, it for the,
anything additional, I mean, is the additional, the, the spend that I would do?
Yeah. So what I would recommend is LSAs, I, I, I forget if we,
I checked my notes. I, I don't think any of them have run for me. Um, okay, I,
so I need to actually go through and get my, uh,
I need to get my business license for Tempe.
'cause I had a Chandler license this last year. Okay.
So I need to get that taken care of. And then they,
we should be able to get those LSAs. Yeah, I, I would say so for LSAs, um,
probably an additional like two to 4,000 per month just depending
on performance. The good thing about those two,
and I would just throw that in honestly, 'cause LSAs aren't hard to manage. Um,
so is that for, and is that for the spend then additional fee?
That would be the, yeah, so our fee would, our,
our fee would be included in the 4,000. I'm happy to throw that in. Oh yeah.
That's per, okay. Yeah. It's, it's honestly Jeremy, like I've,
we've charged before in the past,
but I've been getting called out by so many people on it that they're like,
dude, you're not gonna charge me for that.
'cause I do 'em myself and they're easy.
It's just one of those things where it's like, it,
that only benefits us to do it for you because I know that we can pick up some
phone calls pretty quickly. And it's also tied your,
your L S A listing is tied to your Google Business profile.
We're actively optimizing organically, so it just kind of makes sense for us to,
to manage it. Right. Um, so yeah,
so our fee to manage it is included in that 4,000,
but the ad spend to Google is not Right.
And I would say a minimum of 2000 per month. But if they're going, well, I mean,
obviously we would just scale it up and just turn it off, you know? Yes, yes.
Um, yeah, man, I'm, I mean, honestly, I,
I've talked to quite a few agencies this last week. I mean, you're,
I can tell your,
your heads and shoulders above everybody else just with what you've explained
and gone through and with what your, uh,
what your strategy is and things like that.
So I am 99.9% certain I'm going with you. Um, I, I do wanna,
I do wanna talk it over with my A associates just a little bit. Sure.
Couple things, but I mean, I'm there. There's,
this is really almost a no brainer for me, in all honesty.
I I also recorded this to you, uh, for you, so I'll send it over to you,
so if they wanna watch it and go back through it too. Um, but yeah, I mean,
no rush. Take your time. Um, you know, I'll, I'll,
I'll email all this over to you and, you know,
think about it this week and get back to me next week. And, um, you know,
as soon as you gimme the go ahead then uh, you know,
we can get started the following week. Awesome. Perfect. Alright. Alright,
Jeremy, it was great chatting. You too, Ryan. Alright, I'll,
you'll hear from me soon here. I'll, I'll get back with you pretty soon, so.
Awesome. Alright, well have a good weekend. You too, man. Alright, take bye.